Elon O
Reeve O
Musk B-PER
(/ˈiːlɒn/ O
EE-lon; O
born O
June O
28, O
1971) O
is O
a O
businessman O
known O
for O
his O
key O
roles O
in O
Tesla B-ORG
, O
SpaceX B-ORG
, O
and O
Twitter B-ORG
(which O
he O
rebranded O
as O
X B-ORG
). O
Since O
2025, O
he O
has O
been O
a O
senior O
advisor O
to O
United B-LOC
States I-LOC
president O
Donald B-PER
Trump I-PER
and O
the O
de O
facto O
head O
of O
the O
Department B-ORG
of I-ORG
Government I-ORG
Efficiency I-ORG
(DOGE). O
Musk B-PER
is O
the O
wealthiest O
person O
in O
the O
world; O
as O
of O
March O
2025, O
Forbes B-ORG
estimates O
his O
net O
worth O
to O
be O
$330 O
billion O
USD. O

Born O
to O
a O
wealthy O
family O
in O
Pretoria B-LOC
, O
South B-LOC
Africa I-LOC
, O
Musk B-PER
emigrated O
in O
1989 O
to O
Canada B-LOC
, O
whose O
citizenship O
he O
had O
inherited O
through O
his O
mother. O
He O
graduated O
from O
the O
University B-ORG
of I-ORG
Pennsylvania I-ORG
in O
the O
U.S. B-LOC
before O
moving O
to O
California B-LOC
to O
pursue O
business O
ventures. O
In O
1995, O
Musk B-PER
co-founded O
the O
software O
company O
Zip2 B-ORG
. O
Following O
its O
sale O
in O
1999, O
he O
co-founded O
X.com B-ORG
, O
an O
online O
payment O
company O
that O
later O
merged O
to O
form O
PayPal B-ORG
, O
which O
was O
acquired O
by O
eBay B-ORG
in O
2002 O
for O
$1.5 O
billion. O
That O
year, O
Musk B-PER
also O
became O
a O
U.S. B-LOC
citizen. O

In O
2002, O
Musk B-PER
founded O
SpaceX B-ORG
and O
became O
its O
CEO O
and O
chief O
engineer. O
The O
company O
has O
since O
led O
innovations O
in O
reusable O
rockets O
and O
commercial O
spaceflight. O
In O
2004, O
Musk B-PER
joined O
Tesla B-ORG
, O
Inc. I-ORG
, O
as O
an O
early O
investor, O
and O
became O
its O
CEO O
and O
product O
architect O
in O
2008; O
it O
has O
become O
a O
market O
leader O
in O
electric O
vehicles. O
In O
2015, O
he O
co-founded O
OpenAI B-ORG
to O
advance O
artificial O
intelligence O
research, O
but O
left O
its O
board O
in O
2018. O
In O
2016, O
Musk B-PER
co-founded O
Neuralink B-ORG
, O
a O
company O
focused O
on O
brain–computer O
interfaces, O
and O
in O
2017 O
launched O
the O
Boring B-ORG
Company I-ORG
, O
which O
aims O
to O
develop O
tunnel O
transportation. O
Musk B-PER
was O
named O
Time B-ORG
magazine's O
Person O
of O
the O
Year O
in O
2021. O
In O
2022, O
he O
acquired O
Twitter B-ORG
, O
implementing O
significant O
changes O
and O
rebranding O
it O
as O
X B-ORG
in O
2023. O
In O
January O
2025, O
he O
was O
appointed O
head O
of O
Trump B-PER
's O
newly O
created O
DOGE B-ORG
. O

Musk B-PER
's O
political O
activities O
and O
views O
have O
made O
him O
a O
polarizing O
figure. O
He O
has O
been O
criticized O
for O
making O
unscientific O
and O
misleading O
statements, O
including O
COVID-19 B-MISC
misinformation O
and O
promoting O
conspiracy O
theories. O
His O
acquisition O
of O
Twitter B-ORG
(now O
X B-ORG
) O
was O
controversial O
due O
to O
a O
subsequent O
increase O
in O
hate O
speech O
and O
the O
spread O
of O
misinformation O
on O
the O
service. O
He O
has O
engaged O
in O
political O
activities O
in O
several O
countries, O
including O
as O
a O
vocal O
and O
financial O
supporter O
of O
Trump B-PER
. O
Musk B-PER
was O
the O
largest O
donor O
in O
the O
2024 O
U.S. B-LOC
presidential O
election O
and O
is O
a O
supporter O
of O
global O
far-right O
figures, O
causes, O
and O
political O
parties. O

Musk B-PER
attended O
Waterkloof B-ORG
House I-ORG
Preparatory I-ORG
School I-ORG
, O
Bryanston B-ORG
High I-ORG
School I-ORG
, O
and O
then O
Pretoria B-ORG
Boys I-ORG
High I-ORG
School I-ORG
, O
where O
he O
graduated. O
Musk B-PER
was O
a O
good O
but O
unexceptional O
student, O
earning O
a O
61 O
in O
Afrikaans B-MISC
and O
a O
B O
on O
his O
senior O
math O
certification. O
Musk B-PER
applied O
for O
a O
Canadian B-MISC
passport O
through O
his O
Canadian-born O
mother O
to O
avoid O
South B-LOC
Africa I-LOC
's O
mandatory O
military O
service, O
which O
would O
have O
forced O
him O
to O
participate O
in O
the O
apartheid B-MISC
regime, O
as O
well O
as O
to O
ease O
his O
path O
to O
immigration O
to O
the O
United B-LOC
States I-LOC
. O
While O
waiting O
for O
his O
application O
to O
be O
processed, O
he O
attended O
the O
University B-ORG
of I-ORG
Pretoria I-ORG
for O
five O
months. O

Musk B-PER
arrived O
in O
Canada B-LOC
in O
June O
1989, O
connected O
with O
a O
second O
cousin O
in O
Saskatchewan B-LOC
, O
and O
worked O
odd O
jobs O
including O
at O
a O
farm O
and O
a O
lumber O
mill. O
In O
1990, O
he O
entered O
Queen's B-ORG
University I-ORG
in O
Kingston B-LOC
, O
Ontario B-LOC
. O
Two O
years O
later, O
he O
transferred O
to O
the O
University B-ORG
of I-ORG
Pennsylvania I-ORG
, O
where O
he O
studied O
until O
1995. O
Although O
Musk B-PER
has O
said O
that O
he O
earned O
his O
degrees O
in O
1995, O
the O
University B-ORG
of I-ORG
Pennsylvania I-ORG
did O
not O
award O
them O
until O
1997 O
– O
a O
Bachelor O
of O
Arts O
in O
physics O
and O
a O
Bachelor O
of O
Science O
in O
economics O
from O
the O
university's O
Wharton B-ORG
School I-ORG
. O
He O
reportedly O
hosted O
large, O
ticketed O
house O
parties O
to O
help O
pay O
for O
tuition, O
and O
wrote O
a O
business O
plan O
for O
an O
electronic O
book-scanning O
service O
similar O
to O
Google B-ORG
Books I-ORG
. O

In O
1994, O
Musk B-PER
held O
two O
internships O
in O
Silicon B-LOC
Valley I-LOC
: O
one O
at O
energy O
storage O
startup O
Pinnacle B-ORG
Research I-ORG
Institute I-ORG
, O
which O
investigated O
electrolytic O
supercapacitors O
for O
energy O
storage, O
and O
another O
at O
Palo B-LOC
Alto I-LOC
–based O
startup O
Rocket B-ORG
Science I-ORG
Games I-ORG
. O
In O
1995, O
he O
was O
accepted O
to O
a O
graduate O
program O
in O
materials O
science O
at O
Stanford B-ORG
University I-ORG
, O
but O
did O
not O
enroll. O
Musk B-PER
decided O
to O
join O
the O
Internet O
boom, O
applying O
for O
a O
job O
at O
Netscape B-ORG
, O
to O
which O
he O
reportedly O
never O
received O
a O
response. O
The O
Washington B-ORG
Post I-ORG
reported O
that O
Musk B-PER
lacked O
legal O
authorization O
to O
remain O
and O
work O
in O
the O
United B-LOC
States I-LOC
after O
failing O
to O
enroll O
at O
Stanford B-ORG
. O
In O
response, O
Musk B-PER
said O
he O
was O
allowed O
to O
work O
at O
that O
time O
and O
that O
his O
student O
visa O
transitioned O
to O
an O
H1-B. O
According O
to O
numerous O
former O
business O
associates O
and O
shareholders, O
Musk B-PER
said O
he O
was O
on O
a O
student O
visa O
at O
the O
time. O

Elon B-PER
Musk I-PER
is O
the O
wealthiest O
person O
in O
the O
world, O
with O
an O
estimated O
net O
worth O
of O
US$ O
330 O
billion O
as O
of O
March O
2025, O
according O
to O
the O
Bloomberg B-ORG
Billionaires I-ORG
Index I-ORG
, O
and O
$359.5 O
billion O
according O
to O
Forbes B-ORG
, O
primarily O
from O
his O
ownership O
stakes O
in O
Tesla B-ORG
and O
SpaceX B-ORG
. O

Having O
been O
first O
listed O
on O
the O
Forbes B-ORG
Billionaires I-ORG
List I-ORG
in O
2012, O
around O
75% O
of O
Musk B-PER
's O
wealth O
was O
derived O
from O
Tesla B-ORG
stock O
in O
November O
2020. O
Describing O
himself O
as O
"cash O
poor", O
a O
year O
later, O
he O
became O
the O
first O
person O
in O
the O
world O
to O
have O
a O
net O
worth O
above O
$300 O
billion. O
By O
December O
2024, O
he O
became O
the O
first O
person O
to O
reach O
a O
net O
worth O
of O
$400 O
billion. O

Musk B-PER
is O
president O
of O
the O
Musk B-ORG
Foundation I-ORG
he O
founded O
in O
2001, O
whose O
stated O
purpose O
is O
to O
provide O
solar-power O
energy O
systems O
in O
disaster O
areas, O
with O
an O
interest O
in O
human O
space O
exploration, O
pediatrics, O
renewable O
energy, O
and O
"safe O
artificial O
intelligence". O
From O
2002 O
to O
2018, O
the O
foundation O
donated O
nearly O
half O
of O
its O
$25 O
million O
directly O
to O
Musk B-PER
's O
OpenAI B-ORG
. O
The O
foundation's O
assets O
reached O
$9.4 O
billion O
by O
the O
end O
of O
2021, O
but O
it O
only O
dispensed O
$160 O
million O
to O
charities O
that O
year. O

The O
Musk B-ORG
Foundation I-ORG
has O
been O
criticized O
for O
its O
"self-serving" O
donations O
to O
efforts O
close O
to O
Musk B-PER
's O
family O
and O
companies, O
as O
well O
as O
its O
low O
payout O
ratio. O
In O
2021, O
after O
Musk B-PER
challenged O
World B-ORG
Food I-ORG
Programme I-ORG
director O
David B-PER
Beasley I-PER
to O
draft O
a O
plan O
to O
use O
money O
of O
Musk B-PER
's O
that O
Beasley B-PER
said O
could O
contribute O
to O
ending O
world O
hunger, O
Musk B-PER
instead O
donated O
the O
$6 O
billion O
in O
question O
to O
his O
own O
foundation O
even O
after O
Beasley B-PER
's O
plan O
showed O
that O
the O
money O
could O
feed O
42 O
million O
people O
for O
a O
year. O